Christina E. Simmons

C (919) 412-0997

105 Arbor Dr. Elon, NC 27244

cesimmons84@gmail.com

Summary:

Professional with several years' experience as a telecommunicator and 911 dispatcher seeking a change in career to web development. Key competencies include; multi-tasking, ability to learn new technology quickly, team player, creative and organized. Personal skills include: handling criticism well, resourceful and motivated. Ability to remain calm in stressful situations.

Education:

Western Carolina University - Cullowhee, NC

Bachelor of Science Degree in Criminal Justice and Emergency Management GPA 3.18 – 2006

Professional Experience:

Telecommunicator/Dispatcher 5-2012 to Present

Holly Springs Police Department - Holly Springs, NC

Responsibilities:

Work with local, state and federal agencies

Manage multiple calls for service

Prioritize calls based on degree of urgency

Refer or resolve citizen issues

Trained new employee

Patrol Telecommunicator 12-2007 to 10-2010 and 2-2011 to 5-2012

North Carolina State Highway Patrol - Raleigh, NC

Responsibilities:

Developed multitasking, prioritization and organizational skills simultaneously working a multi-channel radio console, phones, NAWAS circuits, and DCI console

Worked as a team player with several coworkers everyday assisting with tasks when needed, contributing to ease workflow and maintain patrol standards

Formed professional relationships with coworkers and other emergency personnel working with local, state and federal agencies

Maintained critical data for the State of North Carolina regarding absconders

Information Processing Technician 11-2010 to 2-2011

North Carolina Department of Corrections - Raleigh, NC

Responsibilities:

Perform DCI functions

Enter, file, locate, validate and clear warrants

Maintain records on absconders, parolees, probationers and wanted subjects

Assist citizens and probation/parole officers

Specialist 1 Emergency Comm. 5-2006 to 10-2006 and 1-2007 to 8-2007

City of Greensboro – Greensboro, NC

Responsibilities:

Introduced and adapted well to new office environment and policies

Began forming professional working relationships

Managed and updated critical data for first responders

Learned new program and taught pilot program to supervisors of first responders